hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and in this podcast we
talk about how to grow your coaching
business online course and mentorship
business I want to talk today about the
differences between an evergreen funnel
and a live event funnel and we've done
both of these very successfully uh we've
been scaling our businesses with both of
them and I've been doing this for years
I've been in the online marketing space
for nearly 22 years when we started we
were doing almost everything was like
Evergreen then this whole thing of
challenges and and live webinars became
a big Trend and now what we're noticing
is a a blend a hybrid approach is the
one that we're really liking to take
because of how it allows us to leverage
our lead generation
efforts and get the best results out
there and so what I want to break down
for you is kind of the nuances and the
differences between the two um and the
pros and cons between them so number one
is that a both of them are kind of the
form of a webinar or a challenge so
think about this what's a webinar or a
challenge so a webinar or challenge is
is a live video training where somebody
registers with their name and email
address or they pay for it and you're
providing value to people in the form of
video and you're almost always going to
be selling something at the end of it or
during the event that's one of the
things that I think a lot of people they
don't realize before they're getting
into the industry before they getting
into the business is that you you
utilize these these are your best tools
for actually selling and getting people
to become your clients is having these
different trainings but what you want to
do you want to get as many people pushed
into the trainings as possible just
having videos out there just having
YouTube videos just having content out
there isn't enough to actually convert
to clients and so what you want to do is
you want to have it to where it's a
sequence where people give you their
email
address and then they watch a video and
then in the video they are made an offer
to something to buy that's really the
three steps or three stages of an
effective funnel in how we build it
people find you on social media they
give you their email
address okay so like they're going to
type in their email
address this marker is a little dead
right here if you're watching on YouTube
you you'll be able to see the video from
there they watch some sort of video
content and then you make them an offer
of some kind that's going to cost them
money and this is the process this is as
old as time this is the best process for
growing online course or coaching
businesses so again the aspect that like
these two stages right here those change
over time those get different whether it
be Instagram reels whether it be uh
Facebook ads whether it be Tik Tok
whether it be YouTube all these
different things that lead to that for
instance this YouTube video right now
below this video you'll find links to
check out some of the free classes that
I have where you sign up with your email
address you're going to be able to watch
a video class and news flash hint yes in
it I make you an offer but I also
provide a lot of value in those videos
okay and so that's exactly what that is
the difference is when you do it
live it happens on a specific day so you
pick a day December 19th 2024 okay and
that's when people need to show up and
so all roads are converging towards this
event now it's really cool is because of
the energy of a live event and it
happening on a specific day you can
really persuade and motivate more people
to really build up to a live event and
they they will usually be far more
attended and they will often convert to
sales better here's the problem though
you can only do them once you do it once
you do on one event and that's it so in
Evergreen funnel the difference is you
can do them every single day you have
the video content people can access it
today they can access it tomorrow they
can access it next week you can go check
out the ones I have below this video you
can access it right now go watch the
video and it doesn't matter whether I'm
doing it live or not and I found that
this works really well for my schedule
for my lifestyle of having two two kids
under 2 years old um and building a
multi-million dollar online coaching
business that we have and we found that
this really helps because it allows us
to provide value to people it allows us
to sell our programs and they and it
works really well we've got like dozens
of new clients through these different
funnels and these different
processes and they work really well now
we were able to scale our business with
Live Events and Live Events work great
you're going to sell more on a live
event so I want I'm going to give you
this one of the main pros and cons
between Evergreen versus live event
you're going to have more
people per registration who actually
become a
committed final sale with you on a live
event overall okay whereas a
Evergreen is that you can increase the
volume because you can promote it longer
you can push more people through it and
you can actually relax a little bit take
some time off and have it continue
promoting and make you money while you
sleep and so those are the different
pros and cons now what I like to do is I
like to do a blend of these and this is
what we're doing with our clients this
what we're doing our own business is
we're promoting okay
Evergreen
Evergreen have a new one we're about to
launch
Evergreen these people are all going
onto our email list
okay and off of that email list I'm able
to send people the YouTube videos that
we're creating so what that does is that
allows us to
nurture the relationship with somebody
who signs up through these Evergreen
funnels and and if they become a client
great they can do that but the but then
what we do is ever so often we're going
to end up throwing in a live event that
we end up sending to that audience and
what that'll do is that's going to
connect with people and then some of the
people who maybe didn't become a client
through the ever green or through our
nurture sequences they will become
clients in that live event and this
becomes our our sequence right here as
we're trying to we're we're growing the
email list with the Evergreen trainings
we record a training on video we launch
it out there we get as many people to
register for it as possible we end up
providing value we end up telling people
about our program and then from there
they're on our email list and they get
sent the different videos and things
that we offer okay and so that's one of
the beautiful things about that now with
uh Evergreen you have to plan everything
ahead of time and this is can be
somewhat daunting because it's a lot of
work initially that you got to do you
got to write emails you got to create
all the landing pages you got to create
all the thank you Pages you got to
create the presentation you have to do
the presentation to essentially
nobody um which kind of if you're not
used to doing that your energy might be
a little bit low and so with that you
have to learn how to actually train
yourself to actually keep your energy
high as if you're doing it live even
though it's Evergreen okay and then you
have to direct people to some kind of an
offer using a tool like deadline funnel
to be able to get people uh have a
limited time to sign up for your offer
having some kind of a limited time offer
whether it be an expiring bonus a
discount something that they they don't
get access to after a certain period of
time and it being available only for a
select group of people is really really
valuable to your funnel and your ability
to actually close sales now the benefit
of a live event is that you're leading
everybody to show up to this one event
to this one moment to this one
opportunity with you to this one
sequence and then from
there you get everybody in one room
together and you're able to sell to them
and then your limited time is basically
another of event for 4 days after that
where you can open and close the doors
or you have a limited time discount or
something that you're offering people to
encourage them to take action to jump in
to do something to act and move forward
with you and so those are really the
benefits of doing a live event now one
or the other here here's the thing you
might say I don't know which one's
better they're different okay I would
recommend if you're just starting out in
your business to do some Live Events we
structure them the same way that it's
you got people register for an email
they're they're going to join you for a
live event and then you're going to sell
to them on that live event to be able to
become a client of yours the difference
is with Evergreen is that people can
sign up every single day but your
conversion rates will be a lot lower
let's say you have a 100 people who sign
up for a live event you might get 10
clients off of a 100 people whereas if
you have 100 people who sign up for an
evergreen funnel you might only get two
clients for instance okay and so the
numbers are a lot lower on that but what
ends up happening is is that as you're
nurturing and sending additional offers
to those people the numbers end up
scaling and really when we compare the
amount of hours spent doing Evergreen
versus live Evergreen does come out
ahead because the amount of hours that
you're investing in growing your
business is far lower than in the live
event sequence because you're not having
to constantly show up and constantly
launch a new thing and constantly do
this and so that's again one of the
benefits of doing an evergreen offer and
an evergreen approach and that's what we
help people do inside of my coaching
program the client growth accelerators
we help you work on your offer work on
your landing page work on your
advertising campaigns dial in your
messaging know exactly how to generate
leads how to close sales what to say to
get people to buy from you that you can
have consistent income so you can have
massive impact in your business and so
that you can have the time and Financial
Freedom that you want and so i' i' love
to have you join me in my client growth
accelerator program I'd love to have you
jump in there with us you can find a
link for some information about that
Below in this video we'll talk soon have
a good one
[Music]
[Applause]